<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><origin>Desert Research Institute</origin><pubdate>20170301</pubdate><title>Evapotranspiration data for northwest Nevada for 2002, derived from Landsat imagery and gridded weather products</title><geoform>Vector Digital Data Set (Polygon)</geoform><lworkcit><citeinfo><origin>Justin L. Huntington</origin><origin>Matthew Bromley</origin><origin>Charles G. Morton</origin><origin>Timothy Minor</origin><origin>Greg Pohll</origin><origin>Jim Thomas</origin><pubdate>20161131</pubdate><title>Remote Sensing Estimates of Evapotranspiration from Irrigated Agriculture, Northwestern Nevada</title><geoform>Publication (Other)</geoform></citeinfo></lworkcit></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>Reporting of evapotranspiration from irrigated agriculture in Nevada and other western US states is increasingly being required for surface and groundwater use inventories, estimating historical pumpage, and supporting the evaluation of water right applications, transfers, and protests. The arid landscape of northwestern Nevada is punctuated by agricultural communities that rely on water supplied by the diversion of surface waters, groundwater, or a combination of both. Many hydrographic areas (HAs) within northwestern Nevada are entirely reliant on groundwater due to the lack of surface water, while other HAs are entirely reliant on surface water due to poor quality of groundwater. Precipitation in the form of winter snowfall largely determines the amount of surface water that is available for irrigation the following growing season. During years of insufficient surface water supplies, some basins can use supplemental groundwater in order to meet irrigation needs. Annual and monthly consumptive use from irrigated agriculture is largely a function of surface and groundwater availability, atmospheric water demand, crop type, land use and cropping changes such as fallowing and crop rotations, crop stress and disease, and water right transfers from irrigation to a new use (e.g. municipal or environmental). The use of satellite imagery is required to accurately estimate actual evapotranspiration (ET) from irrigated agriculture. Because crop type and field conditions can vary significantly in time and space, satellite imagery such as Landsat that is of sufficient spatial resolution to capture field scale conditions, is required to accurately characterize spatial and temporal variations of crop phenology, stress, and ultimately ET. Free access to satellite imagery and gridded weather data along with significant advances in processing hardware, software, and analysis, has advanced the use of satellite imagery to the forefront of ET estimation. This is especially true where water consumption from large areas has to be quantified. 
The objective of this study is to estimate monthly an annual ET from agricultural areas in northwestern Nevada from 2001 through 2011 using Landsat satellite imagery. Field scale ET estimates from 57 HAs are summarized multiple ways includeing a geodatabase, maps, figures, and tables. Monthly and annual ET estimates for select HAs are discussed with respect to variations in climate, water supply, and land use changes, through visualizations and summaries of spatial and temporal ET distributions. A geodatabase was constructed ET, precipitation, net ET (ET minus precipitation), and atmospheric water demand (i.e. reference ET). Landsat based ET was estimated using a land surface energy balance model, Mapping EvapoTranspiration at high Resolution with Internalized Calibration (METRIC), using Landsat 5 and Landsat 7 imagery combined with reference ET. Estimates of net ET were created by subtracting monthly precipitation from METRIC-derived ET, and seasonal estimates were generated by combining monthly ET for April-October (the regional agricultural growing season). Results highlight that a range of geographic, climatic, hydrographic, and anthropogenic factors influence ET. For example, HAs such as Mason Valley have the ability to mitigate deficiencies in surface water supplies by pumping supplemental groundwater, thereby resulting in low annual variability of ET. Conversely, Lovelock has access to limited upstream surface water storage and is not able to irrigate with groundwater due to high salinity. These factors result in Lovelock ET being highly variable in time due to drought. ET estimates derived from METRIC compare fairly well to previous estimates of well-irrigated crop ET reported by Huntington and Allen (2010) (i.e. NVET estimates). Differences in ET estimates are potentially due to the fact that previous NVET estimates assume well-irrigated conditions and the fact that METRIC also has limitations and inaccuracies. Although there are limitations and uncertainties with the METRIC model, previous Nevada studies have shown METRIC is fairly accurate for crops of alfalfa and pasture grass. Results of this work will be useful for water use inventories, groundwater use estimation, and in distinguishing how prolonged droughts and changing climate will potentially affect different HAs and agricultural communities in the future.</abstract><purpose>This geodatabase contains shapefiles that contain estimates of evapotranspiration for agricultural areas within northwest Nevada and additional support data. These shapefiles contain data for the years 2001-2011, with each shapefile representing a single year.</purpose></descript><timeperd><timeinfo><rngdates><begdate>20020101</begdate><enddate>20021231</enddate></rngdates></timeinfo><current>observed</current></timeperd><status><progress>Planned</progress><update>None planned</update></status><spdom><bounding><westbc>-121.015437869</westbc><eastbc>-116.899008196</eastbc><northbc>41.17632953</northbc><southbc>38.111773715</southbc></bounding></spdom><keywords><theme><themekt>Marine Realms Information Bank (MRIB) keywords</themekt><themekey>evapotranspiration measurements</themekey></theme><theme><themekt>USGS Thesaurus</themekt><themekey>evaporation</themekey><themekey>transpiration</themekey><themekey>agriculture</themekey><themekey>water use</themekey></theme><place><placekt>Common geographic areas</placekt><placekey>Nevada</placekey><placekey>California North</placekey></place></keywords><accconst>None. Please see 'Distribution Info' for details.</accconst><useconst>None. Users are advised to read the data set's metadata thoroughly to understand appropriate use and data limitations.</useconst><datacred>This work was funded by the Bureau of Reclamation, in cooperation with State of Nevada.</datacred><native>Environment as of Metadata Creation: Microsoft Windows 7 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; Esri ArcGIS 10.3.1 (Build 4959) Service Pack N/A (Build N/A)</native></idinfo><dataqual><attracc><attraccr>No formal attribute accuracy tests were conducted.</attraccr></attracc><logic>No formal logical accuracy tests were conducted.</logic><complete>Data set is considered complete for the information presented, as described in the abstract. Users are advised to read the rest of the metadata record carefully for additional details.</complete><posacc><horizpa><horizpar>A formal accuracy assessment of the horizontal positional information in the data set has not been conducted.</horizpar></horizpa><vertacc><vertaccr>A formal accuracy assessment of the vertical positional information in the data set has either not been conducted, or is not applicable.</vertaccr></vertacc></posacc><lineage><srcinfo><srccite><citeinfo><origin>PRISM Climate Group</origin><pubdate>20040204</pubdate><title>PRISM Gridded Climate Data</title><geoform>Raster Digital Data Set</geoform><pubinfo><pubplace>Oregon State University, Corvallis, OR</pubplace><publish>PRISM Climate Group</publish></pubinfo><onlink>http://prism.oregonstate.edu</onlink></citeinfo></srccite><typesrc>Digital and/or Hardcopy Resources</typesrc><srctime><timeinfo><rngdates><begdate>20020101</begdate><enddate>20021231</enddate></rngdates></timeinfo><srccurr>ground condition</srccurr></srctime><srccitea>PRISM Gridded Climate Data</srccitea><srccontr>Precipitation data.</srccontr></srcinfo><srcinfo><srccite><citeinfo><origin>University of Idaho</origin><pubdate>2012</pubdate><title>gridMET/METDATA</title><geoform>Raster Digital Data Set</geoform><pubinfo><pubplace>University of Idaho, Moscow, ID</pubplace><publish>University of Idaho</publish></pubinfo><onlink>http://climate.nkn.uidaho.edu/METDATA/</onlink></citeinfo></srccite><typesrc>Digital and/or Hardcopy Resources</typesrc><srctime><timeinfo><rngdates><begdate>20020101</begdate><enddate>20021231</enddate></rngdates></timeinfo><srccurr>observed</srccurr></srctime><srccitea>Source Input 2</srccitea><srccontr>Source information used in support of the development of the data set.</srccontr></srcinfo><srcinfo><srccite><citeinfo><origin>USGS Earth Resources Observation and Science (EROS) Center</origin><title>Landsat Imagery</title><geoform>Raster Digital Data (Aerial Imagery)</geoform><pubinfo><pubplace>Sioux Falls, SD</pubplace><publish>USGS Earth Resources Observation and Science (EROS) Center</publish></pubinfo><onlink>http://landsat.usgs.gov/</onlink></citeinfo></srccite><typesrc>Digital and/or Hardcopy Resources</typesrc><srctime><timeinfo><rngdates><begdate>20020101</begdate><enddate>20021231</enddate></rngdates></timeinfo><srccurr>observed</srccurr></srctime><srccitea>Landsat Imagery</srccitea><srccontr>Source information used in support of the development of the data set.</srccontr></srcinfo><procstep><procdesc>Development of the data set by the agency / individuals identified in the 'Originator' element in the Identification Info section of the record.</procdesc><procdate>Unknown</procdate></procstep></lineage></dataqual><spdoinfo><direct>Vector</direct><ptvctinf><sdtsterm><sdtstype>G-polygon</sdtstype><ptvctcnt>7793</ptvctcnt></sdtsterm></ptvctinf></spdoinfo><spref><horizsys><planar><gridsys><gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn><utm><utmzone>11</utmzone><transmer><sfctrmer>0.9996</sfctrmer><longcm>-117.0</longcm><latprjo>0.0</latprjo><feast>500000.0</feast><fnorth>0.0</fnorth></transmer></utm></gridsys><planci><plance>coordinate pair</plance><coordrep><absres>0.6096</absres><ordres>0.6096</ordres></coordrep><plandu>Meter</plandu></planci></planar><geodetic><horizdn>D_WGS_1984</horizdn><ellips>WGS_1984</ellips><semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis><denflat>298.257223563</denflat></geodetic></horizsys></spref><eainfo><detailed Name="Merged_2002"><enttyp><enttypl>Attribute Table</enttypl><enttypd>Table containing attribute information associated with the data set.</enttypd><enttypds>Producer defined</enttypds></enttyp><attr><attrlabl>BASIN</attrlabl><attrdef>This attribute was used for the processing of hydrographic areas (HAs) within the study area, in order to bypass conflicts with naming methods employed in Nevada and California.</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Unknown</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>STATE</attrlabl><attrdef>State which contains the centroid of the polygon.</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><edom><edomv>CA</edomv><edomvd>California</edomvd><edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds></edom></attrdomv><attrdomv><edom><edomv>NV</edomv><edomvd>Nevada</edomvd><edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds></edom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>HYD_AREA</attrlabl><attrdef>The number designator assigned to the hydrographic area (HA) in which the centroid of the polygon is located.  For areas in California, the attribute is assigned a value of: “CA”.</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Unknown</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>HYD_AREA_N</attrlabl><attrdef>The name assigned to the hydrographic area (HA), in which the centroid of the polygon is located.</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Unknown</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>HUC8</attrlabl><attrdef>For locations in California a hydrologic unit code (HUC) was used to denote the basin containing the polygon.  Attribute utilizes that HUC8 code.</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Unknown</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>HUC8_NAME</attrlabl><attrdef>For locations in California a hydrologic unit code (HUC) was used to denote the basin containing the polygon. Attribute utilizes the name associated with the HUC8.</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom>Unknown</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PIXELCOUNT</attrlabl><attrdef>The number of pixels contained within the polygon.</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>32284</rdommax><attrunit>Number of pixels</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>YEAR</attrlabl><attrdef>The year for which the data was generated.</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>2002</rdommin><rdommax>2002</rdommax><attrunit>Year</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>AREA</attrlabl><attrdef>Area contained within pixel (acres)</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>1.4501631053E-05</rdommin><rdommax>7574.98839236</rdommax><attrunit>acres</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETR_ANNUAL</attrlabl><attrdef>Annual total of reference evapotranspiration (ETr) calculated for the polygon (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>1890.19995117188</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ET_ANNUAL</attrlabl><attrdef>Annual total of evapotranspiration (ET) calculated for the polygon (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>1574.94995117188</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETRF_ANNUL</attrlabl><attrdef>Annual average of fraction of reference evapotranspiration (ETrF) (unitless)</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>0.932856023311615</rdommax><attrunit>unitless</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PPT_ANNUAL</attrlabl><attrdef>Annual total of precipitation (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>PRISM Climate Group, Oregon State University, http://prism.oregonstate.edu, created 4 Feb 2004.</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>75.3769989013672</rdommin><rdommax>1085.09997558594</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>NET_ANNUAL</attrlabl><attrdef>Annual total of ET with the annual total of precipitation subtracted (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>-1085.09997558594</rdommin><rdommax>1380.57995605469</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETR_SEASON</attrlabl><attrdef>Seasonal total of reference evapotranspiration (ETr) for the polygon (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>1536.10998535156</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ET_SEASON</attrlabl><attrdef>Seasonal total of evapotranspiration (ET) for the polygon (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>1400.5400390625</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETRF_SEASN</attrlabl><attrdef>Seasonal average of fraction of reference evapotranspiration (ETrF) (unitless)</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>0.927908003330231</rdommax><attrunit>unitless</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PPT_SEASON</attrlabl><attrdef>Seasonal total of precipitation (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>22.609899520874</rdommin><rdommax>107.814002990723</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>NET_SEASON</attrlabl><attrdef>Seasonal total of net evapotranspiration (ET-PPT) (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>-107.814002990723</rdommin><rdommax>1322.14001464844</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>START_MON</attrlabl><attrdef>Attribute corresponds to the month that was selected to serve as the start of the agricultural growing season.  This attribute was used with END_MON to generate seasonal totals.  The default value selected for the study area was “4”, corresponding to the month of April.</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>4</rdommin><rdommax>4</rdommax><attrunit>month</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>END_MON</attrlabl><attrdef>Attribute corresponds to the month that was selected to serve as the end of the agricultural growing season.  This attribute was used with START_MON to generate seasonal totals.  The default value selected for the study area was “10”, corresponding to the month of October.</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>10</rdommin><rdommax>10</rdommax><attrunit>month</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETR_M01</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly total of reference evapotranspiration (ETr) for the polygon during the month of January.  Reference evaporation produced from the GridMET dataset (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>52.5700988769531</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETR_M02</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly total of reference evapotranspiration (ETr) for the polygon during the month of February.  Reference evaporation produced from the GridMET dataset (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>85.4886016845703</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETR_M03</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly total of reference evapotranspiration (ETr) for the polygon during the month of March.  Reference evaporation produced from the GridMET dataset (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>135.399002075195</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETR_M04</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly total of reference evapotranspiration (ETr) for the polygon during the month of April.  Reference evaporation produced from the GridMET dataset (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>172.766006469727</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETR_M05</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly total of reference evapotranspiration (ETr) for the polygon during the month of May.  Reference evaporation produced from the GridMET dataset (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>223.483001708984</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETR_M06</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly total of reference evapotranspiration (ETr) for the polygon during the month of June.  Reference evaporation produced from the GridMET dataset (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>277.273010253906</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETR_M07</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly total of reference evapotranspiration (ETr) for the polygon during the month of July.  Reference evaporation produced from the GridMET dataset (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>311.550994873047</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETR_M08</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly total of reference evapotranspiration (ETr) for the polygon during the month of August.  Reference evaporation produced from the GridMET dataset (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>264.406005859375</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETR_M09</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly total of reference evapotranspiration (ETr) for the polygon during the month of September.  Reference evaporation produced from the GridMET dataset (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>201.824996948242</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETR_M10</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly total of reference evapotranspiration (ETr) for the polygon during the month of October.  Reference evaporation produced from the GridMET dataset (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>133.955993652344</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETR_M11</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly total of reference evapotranspiration (ETr) for the polygon during the month of November.  Reference evaporation produced from the GridMET dataset (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>68.5462036132813</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETR_M12</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly total of reference evapotranspiration (ETr) for the polygon during the month of December.  Reference evaporation produced from the GridMET dataset (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>45.4492988586426</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ET_M01</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly total of calculated evapotranspiration (ET) for the area contained within the polygon for the month of January (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>47.4777984619141</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ET_M02</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly total of calculated evapotranspiration (ET) for the area contained within the polygon for the month of February (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>114.15599822998</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ET_M03</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly total of calculated evapotranspiration (ET) for the area contained within the polygon for the month of March (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>141.779006958008</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ET_M04</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly total of calculated evapotranspiration (ET) for the area contained within the polygon for the month of April (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>179.125</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ET_M05</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly total of calculated evapotranspiration (ET) for the area contained within the polygon for the month of May (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>224.998992919922</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ET_M06</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly total of calculated evapotranspiration (ET) for the area contained within the polygon for the month of June (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>279.558990478516</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ET_M07</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly total of calculated evapotranspiration (ET) for the area contained within the polygon for the month of July (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>302.239013671875</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ET_M08</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly total of calculated evapotranspiration (ET) for the area contained within the polygon for the month of August (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>261.213989257813</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ET_M09</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly total of calculated evapotranspiration (ET) for the area contained within the polygon for the month of September (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>197.248001098633</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ET_M10</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly total of calculated evapotranspiration (ET) for the area contained within the polygon for the month of October (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>139.033004760742</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ET_M11</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly total of calculated evapotranspiration (ET) for the area contained within the polygon for the month of November (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>116.009002685547</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ET_M12</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly total of calculated evapotranspiration (ET) for the area contained within the polygon for the month of December (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>51.3474998474121</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETRF_M01</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly average of fraction of reference evapotranspiration(ETrF) for the month of January for the area contained within the polygon (unitless).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>1.40919005870819</rdommax><attrunit>unitless</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETRF_M02</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly average of fraction of reference evapotranspiration(ETrF) for the month of February for the area contained within the polygon (unitless).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>1.85456001758575</rdommax><attrunit>unitless</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETRF_M03</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly average of fraction of reference evapotranspiration(ETrF) for the month of March for the area contained within the polygon (unitless).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>1.3019700050354</rdommax><attrunit>unitless</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETRF_M04</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly average of fraction of reference evapotranspiration(ETrF) for the month of April for the area contained within the polygon (unitless).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>1.13494002819061</rdommax><attrunit>unitless</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETRF_M05</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly average of fraction of reference evapotranspiration(ETrF) for the month of May for the area contained within the polygon (unitless).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>1.05753004550934</rdommax><attrunit>unitless</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETRF_M06</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly average of fraction of reference evapotranspiration(ETrF) for the month of June for the area contained within the polygon (unitless).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>1.07076001167297</rdommax><attrunit>unitless</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETRF_M07</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly average of fraction of reference evapotranspiration(ETrF) for the month of July for the area contained within the polygon (unitless).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>1.02432000637054</rdommax><attrunit>unitless</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETRF_M08</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly average of fraction of reference evapotranspiration(ETrF) for the month of August for the area contained within the polygon (unitless).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>1.0623699426651</rdommax><attrunit>unitless</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETRF_M09</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly average of fraction of reference evapotranspiration(ETrF) for the month of September for the area contained within the polygon (unitless).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>0.993234992027283</rdommax><attrunit>unitless</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETRF_M10</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly average of fraction of reference evapotranspiration(ETrF) for the month of October for the area contained within the polygon (unitless).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>1.36410999298096</rdommax><attrunit>unitless</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETRF_M11</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly average of fraction of reference evapotranspiration(ETrF) for the month of November for the area contained within the polygon (unitless).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>1.86523997783661</rdommax><attrunit>unitless</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>ETRF_M12</attrlabl><attrdef>Monthly average of fraction of reference evapotranspiration(ETrF) for the month of December for the area contained within the polygon (unitless).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0</rdommin><rdommax>1.4875500202179</rdommax><attrunit>unitless</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PPT_M01</attrlabl><attrdef>Precipitation received by the polygon during the month of January.  Precipitation data acquired from the PRISM daily precipitation product (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>PRISM Climate Group, Oregon State University, http://prism.oregonstate.edu, created 4 Feb 2004.</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>6.14243984222412</rdommin><rdommax>118.709999084473</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PPT_M02</attrlabl><attrdef>Precipitation received by the polygon during the month of February.  Precipitation data acquired from the PRISM daily precipitation product (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>PRISM Climate Group, Oregon State University, http://prism.oregonstate.edu, created 4 Feb 2004.</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>3.33800005912781</rdommin><rdommax>75.2757034301758</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PPT_M03</attrlabl><attrdef>Precipitation received by the polygon during the month of March.  Precipitation data acquired from the PRISM daily precipitation product (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>PRISM Climate Group, Oregon State University, http://prism.oregonstate.edu, created 4 Feb 2004.</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>5.71786022186279</rdommin><rdommax>134.707000732422</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PPT_M04</attrlabl><attrdef>Precipitation received by the polygon during the month of April.  Precipitation data acquired from the PRISM daily precipitation product (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>PRISM Climate Group, Oregon State University, http://prism.oregonstate.edu, created 4 Feb 2004.</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>6.88649988174438</rdommin><rdommax>49.2317008972168</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PPT_M05</attrlabl><attrdef>Precipitation received by the polygon during the month of May.  Precipitation data acquired from the PRISM daily precipitation product (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>PRISM Climate Group, Oregon State University, http://prism.oregonstate.edu, created 4 Feb 2004.</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>3.4817099571228</rdommin><rdommax>31.9958000183105</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PPT_M06</attrlabl><attrdef>Precipitation received by the polygon during the month of June.  Precipitation data acquired from the PRISM daily precipitation product (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>PRISM Climate Group, Oregon State University, http://prism.oregonstate.edu, created 4 Feb 2004.</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0.409862011671066</rdommin><rdommax>17.7604007720947</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PPT_M07</attrlabl><attrdef>Precipitation received by the polygon during the month of July.  Precipitation data acquired from the PRISM daily precipitation product (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>PRISM Climate Group, Oregon State University, http://prism.oregonstate.edu, created 4 Feb 2004.</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>2.32834005355835</rdommin><rdommax>12.4083003997803</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PPT_M08</attrlabl><attrdef>Precipitation received by the polygon during the month of August.  Precipitation data acquired from the PRISM daily precipitation product (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>PRISM Climate Group, Oregon State University, http://prism.oregonstate.edu, created 4 Feb 2004.</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0.404525995254517</rdommin><rdommax>11.3737001419067</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PPT_M09</attrlabl><attrdef>Precipitation received by the polygon during the month of September.  Precipitation data acquired from the PRISM daily precipitation product (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>PRISM Climate Group, Oregon State University, http://prism.oregonstate.edu, created 4 Feb 2004.</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0.1041100025177</rdommin><rdommax>15.4229001998901</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PPT_M10</attrlabl><attrdef>Precipitation received by the polygon during the month of October.  Precipitation data acquired from the PRISM daily precipitation product (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>PRISM Climate Group, Oregon State University, http://prism.oregonstate.edu, created 4 Feb 2004.</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0.93333899974823</rdommin><rdommax>8.9451904296875</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PPT_M11</attrlabl><attrdef>Precipitation received by the polygon during the month of November.  Precipitation data acquired from the PRISM daily precipitation product (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>PRISM Climate Group, Oregon State University, http://prism.oregonstate.edu, created 4 Feb 2004.</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>10.8001003265381</rdommin><rdommax>170.341995239258</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PPT_M12</attrlabl><attrdef>Precipitation received by the polygon during the month of December.  Precipitation data acquired from the PRISM daily precipitation product (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>PRISM Climate Group, Oregon State University, http://prism.oregonstate.edu, created 4 Feb 2004.</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>11.9331998825073</rdommin><rdommax>492.027008056641</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PPTEFF_M01</attrlabl><attrdef>Effective precipitation.  This value was calculated as 90% of the precipitation received at the polygon location for the month of January (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>5.52820014953613</rdommin><rdommax>106.838996887207</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PPTEFF_M02</attrlabl><attrdef>Effective precipitation.  This value was calculated as 90% of the precipitation received at the polygon location for the month of February (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>3.00419998168945</rdommin><rdommax>67.7481002807617</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PPTEFF_M03</attrlabl><attrdef>Effective precipitation.  This value was calculated as 90% of the precipitation received at the polygon location for the month of March (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>5.14607000350952</rdommin><rdommax>121.236000061035</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PPTEFF_M04</attrlabl><attrdef>Effective precipitation.  This value was calculated as 90% of the precipitation received at the polygon location for the month of April (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>6.19785022735596</rdommin><rdommax>44.3084983825684</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PPTEFF_M05</attrlabl><attrdef>Effective precipitation.  This value was calculated as 90% of the precipitation received at the polygon location for the month of May (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>3.13353991508484</rdommin><rdommax>28.796199798584</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PPTEFF_M06</attrlabl><attrdef>Effective precipitation.  This value was calculated as 90% of the precipitation received at the polygon location for the month of June (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0.36887601017952</rdommin><rdommax>15.9843997955322</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PPTEFF_M07</attrlabl><attrdef>Effective precipitation.  This value was calculated as 90% of the precipitation received at the polygon location for the month of July (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>2.09551000595093</rdommin><rdommax>11.1674995422363</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PPTEFF_M08</attrlabl><attrdef>Effective precipitation.  This value was calculated as 90% of the precipitation received at the polygon location for the month of August (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0.364073008298874</rdommin><rdommax>10.2363004684448</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PPTEFF_M09</attrlabl><attrdef>Effective precipitation.  This value was calculated as 90% of the precipitation received at the polygon location for the month of September (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0.0936990007758141</rdommin><rdommax>13.8805999755859</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PPTEFF_M10</attrlabl><attrdef>Effective precipitation.  This value was calculated as 90% of the precipitation received at the polygon location for the month of October (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0.840004980564117</rdommin><rdommax>8.05066967010498</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PPTEFF_M11</attrlabl><attrdef>Effective precipitation.  This value was calculated as 90% of the precipitation received at the polygon location for the month of November (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>9.72008991241455</rdommin><rdommax>153.307998657227</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>PPTEFF_M12</attrlabl><attrdef>Effective precipitation.  This value was calculated as 90% of the precipitation received at the polygon location for the month of December (millimeters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>10.7398996353149</rdommin><rdommax>442.824005126953</rdommax><attrunit>millimeters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>Shape_Length</attrlabl><attrdef>Automatically generated description of the length of the polygon (meters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>5.79428932867873</rdommin><rdommax>53238.0056733518</rdommax><attrunit>meters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr><attr><attrlabl>Shape_Area</attrlabl><attrdef>Automatically generated description of the area contained within the polygon (square meters).</attrdef><attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs><attrdomv><rdom><rdommin>0.0586826421190655</rdommin><rdommax>30654890.3326749</rdommax><attrunit>meters</attrunit></rdom></attrdomv></attr></detailed><overview><eaover>The entity and attribute information provided here describes the tabular data associated with the data set. Please review the detailed descriptions that are provided (the individual attribute descriptions) for information on the values that appear as fields/table entries of the data set.</eaover><eadetcit>The entity and attribute information was generated by the individual and/or agency identified as the originator of the data set. Please review the rest of the metadata record for additional details and information.</eadetcit></overview></eainfo><metainfo><metd>20170228</metd><metc><cntinfo><cntperp><cntper>Matthew Bromley</cntper><cntorg>Desert Reseach Institute</cntorg></cntperp><cntpos>Assistant Research Scientist (GIS/Remote Sensing)</cntpos><cntaddr><addrtype>Mailing and Physical</addrtype><address>2215 Raggio Pkwy</address><city>Reno</city><state>NV</state><postal>89512</postal><country>United States</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>(775) 673-7683</cntvoice><cntemail>MatthewBromley@DRI.edu</cntemail></cntinfo></metc><metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn><metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv></metainfo><Esri><CreaDate>20180105</CreaDate><CreaTime>14484200</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce><DataProperties><lineage><Process ToolSource="c:\program files (x86)\arcgis\desktop10.5\ArcToolbox\Toolboxes\Data Management Tools.tbx\DeleteField" Date="20180105" Time="150034">DeleteField Mason_2002 PPTEFF_M01;PPTEFF_M02;PPTEFF_M03;PPTEFF_M04;PPTEFF_M05;PPTEFF_M06;PPTEFF_M07;PPTEFF_M08;PPTEFF_M09;PPTEFF_M10;PPTEFF_M11;PPTEFF_M12;Shape_Leng;Shape_Area</Process></lineage></DataProperties></Esri></metadata>
